<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.2.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/projects/kaiteki/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/projects/kaiteki/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2023-01-10T23:54:03+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/projects/kaiteki/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Kaiteki</title><entry><title type="html">Week 2022-02 Updates</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/projects/kaiteki/posts/2023/01/08/week-2022-02-updates/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Week 2022-02 Updates" /><published>2023-01-08T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2023-01-08T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/projects/kaiteki/posts/2023/01/08/week-2022-02-updates</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/projects/kaiteki/posts/2023/01/08/week-2022-02-updates/"><![CDATA[<h2 id="blurhash-support">Blurhash support</h2>

<p>Kaiteki now supports displaying blurhashes while or before loading media.</p>

<p>##</p>]]></content><author><name>Craftplacer</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Blurhash support]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">November 2022 Updates</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/projects/kaiteki/posts/2022/11/23/november-2022-updates/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="November 2022 Updates" /><published>2022-11-23T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2022-11-23T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/projects/kaiteki/posts/2022/11/23/november-2022-updates</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/projects/kaiteki/posts/2022/11/23/november-2022-updates/"><![CDATA[<p>Between October and November, focus was laid on bringing essential features to the table.</p>

<h2 id="notifications">Notifications</h2>

<p><img src="/projects/kaiteki/img/november-2022-updates/notifications.jpg" alt="The new notifications screen as seen in Kaiteki, with read and unread tabs and a 'mark all as read' button" /></p>

<p>A basic feature finally joined in, we now have functioning notifications.</p>

<p>It’s not feature complete quite yet, you can check out <a href="https://github.com/Kaiteki-Fedi/Kaiteki/issues/56"><img src="https://img.shields.io/github/issues/detail/state/Kaiteki-Fedi/Kaiteki/56" alt="issue 56" /></a> for more details.</p>

<h2 id="emoji-picker-and-reactions">Emoji picker and reactions</h2>

<p><img src="/projects/kaiteki/img/november-2022-updates/emoji-picker.png" alt="The new emoji picker with tabs and a search bar" /></p>

<p>A proper emoji picker is now available. It also supports Unicode emojis, in order to support reactions.</p>

<h2 id="experimental-twitter-support">Experimental Twitter Support</h2>

<p>Kaiteki now has support for Twitter, although still has many <a href="/projects/kaiteki/compatibility/#twitter">flaws</a>.</p>

<video controls="" muted="">
    <source src="/projects/kaiteki/vid/A9C81CCB.webm" type="video/webm" />
</video>

<h2 id="attachment-changes">Attachment changes</h2>

<h3 id="better-alt-text-support">Better alt text support</h3>

<p><img src="/projects/kaiteki/img/1D6BBD67.png" /></p>

<p>You can properly view the alt text of attachments now. Previously they were displayed in the AppBar, but that was very unfriendly for reading descriptive alt text.</p>

<h2 id="minor-changes">Minor changes</h2>

<ul>
  <li>Fixed <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">ERR_CLEARTEXT_NOT_PERMITTED</code> for Android versions</li>
</ul>]]></content><author><name>Craftplacer</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Between October and November, focus was laid on bringing essential features to the table.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Major quality release</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/projects/kaiteki/posts/2021/11/07/major-quality-release/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Major quality release" /><published>2021-11-07T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2021-11-07T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/projects/kaiteki/posts/2021/11/07/major-quality-release</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/projects/kaiteki/posts/2021/11/07/major-quality-release/"><![CDATA[<p>This new commit batch had many code fixes this time, resulting in less broken elements making Kaiteki more usable.</p>

<h2 id="ui-changes">UI changes</h2>

<ul>
  <li>
    <p>The main screen has a compact navigation rail now with the compose button being permanently visible.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Slight compose dialog redesigns, alongside it being the first dialog to be adaptive to the screen resolution.</p>

    <p>(Try resizing your window while having it open!)</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Post metadata should now have the correct color for the current theme.</p>
  </li>
</ul>

<h2 id="bug-fixes">Bug fixes</h2>

<ul>
  <li>
    <p>Debug post submission has been removed. This slipped into production making it impossible to actually submit posts via Kaiteki.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Rich text will now inherit from the surrounding UI. Expect less black or white text contrasting out of nowhere.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Emojis are now 1.5x of the normal text height, making them more readable.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>The login screen now got its transition animation.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Kaiteki will display a placeholder avatar when the remote image is not accessible.</p>
  </li>
</ul>

<h2 id="code-quality-changes">Code quality changes</h2>

<ul>
  <li>
    <p>ApiToDart has been worked on, ensuring more accurate generation of data classes, Misskey being the one benefiting most out of it.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>The data of API responses are now being saved in another class, to ensure being able to correctly parse error messages in case of any. This also resolves Kaiteki being unable to parse errors from Misskey.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>More default values and fallbacks for Misskey data model conversion.</p>
  </li>
</ul>

<p>and many more minor changes…</p>]]></content><author><name>Craftplacer</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[This new commit batch had many code fixes this time, resulting in less broken elements making Kaiteki more usable. UI changes The main screen has a compact navigation rail now with the compose button being permanently visible. Slight compose dialog redesigns, alongside it being the first dialog to be adaptive to the screen resolution. (Try resizing your window while having it open!) Post metadata should now have the correct color for the current theme. Bug fixes Debug post submission has been removed. This slipped into production making it impossible to actually submit posts via Kaiteki. Rich text will now inherit from the surrounding UI. Expect less black or white text contrasting out of nowhere. Emojis are now 1.5x of the normal text height, making them more readable. The login screen now got its transition animation. Kaiteki will display a placeholder avatar when the remote image is not accessible. Code quality changes ApiToDart has been worked on, ensuring more accurate generation of data classes, Misskey being the one benefiting most out of it. The data of API responses are now being saved in another class, to ensure being able to correctly parse error messages in case of any. This also resolves Kaiteki being unable to parse errors from Misskey. More default values and fallbacks for Misskey data model conversion. and many more minor changes…]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Login experience overhaul</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/projects/kaiteki/posts/2021/10/17/login-experience-overhaul/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Login experience overhaul" /><published>2021-10-17T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2021-10-17T00:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/projects/kaiteki/posts/2021/10/17/login-experience-overhaul</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/projects/kaiteki/posts/2021/10/17/login-experience-overhaul/"><![CDATA[<p>With commit <a href="https://github.com/Craftplacer/Kaiteki/commit/29656d1a9c95076acce269610ac71be8ff23cd88"><code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">29656d1</code></a> the entire login screen was revamped.</p>

<video controls="" muted="">
    <source src="/projects/kaiteki/vid/30EEC26950A328CA.mp4" type="video/mp4" />
    <source src="/projects/kaiteki/vid/3167C3AB3499549B.webm" type="video/webm" />
</video>

<h2 id="new-features">New features</h2>

<ul>
  <li><strong>Instance probing:</strong> No need for knowing what software your instance runs on. Kaiteki will send out requests to known endpoints and will check what kind of instance you have.</li>
  <li><strong>Animations.</strong> (some of them are borked)</li>
  <li><strong>List of “suggested” instances</strong> for Fediverse newcomers, alongside a short description of most instances alongside their rules. (available here)</li>
  <li>Instance logo and background are visible at the login screen</li>
  <li><em>Lots of necessary internal changes</em></li>
</ul>

<h2 id="recent-changes-since-first-announcement">Recent changes since first announcement</h2>

<ul>
  <li>First implementation of keyboard shortcuts, more coming soon</li>
  <li>About screen design changes (now shows Kaiteki’s colorful logo)</li>
  <li>Tooltips on post scope and time (should also aid in screen readers)</li>
  <li>Post time is displayed properly now (If conditions were messed up)</li>
</ul>

<p>You can try these changes now at: <a href="https://kaiteki.craftplacer.moe/">kaiteki.craftplacer.moe</a></p>]]></content><author><name>Craftplacer</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[With commit 29656d1 the entire login screen was revamped. New features Instance probing: No need for knowing what software your instance runs on. Kaiteki will send out requests to known endpoints and will check what kind of instance you have. Animations. (some of them are borked) List of “suggested” instances for Fediverse newcomers, alongside a short description of most instances alongside their rules. (available here) Instance logo and background are visible at the login screen Lots of necessary internal changes Recent changes since first announcement First implementation of keyboard shortcuts, more coming soon About screen design changes (now shows Kaiteki’s colorful logo) Tooltips on post scope and time (should also aid in screen readers) Post time is displayed properly now (If conditions were messed up) You can try these changes now at: kaiteki.craftplacer.moe]]></summary></entry></feed>